Finding Aid for Friars (Musical Group) records,1956-1993
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Friars (Musical Group) records 1956-1993 1963-1992
Friars (Musical Group).
0.4 linear feet
9441 Bimu F19 2
University of Michigan a capella octet formed in 1955, composed of members of the men's glee club. Collection consists of Topical files and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records (Donor 8233 ) were received beginning in 1994. Periodic accessions to continue.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Friars is an a cappella octet named after a turn-of-the-century student organization (drinking club). The Friars originated in 1955 when two rival quartets, the Arbors and the Whatchamacallits, decided to merge their musical talents. In 1960, four members of the Friars decided to form a new group called The Arbors. The new quartet traveled extensively from Minnesota to New York. In 1961 the group recorded an album with Vanguard Recording Company.
The Friars are composed of University of Michigan Men's Glee Club members. The group creates its own choreography and arranges its own music, borrowing from a variety of artists. The octet has been aired on national television and has performed at the White House, the Rose Bowl, and exotic places such as Jamaica, Acapulco, Hawaii and Cancun.
The records span the years 1956-1993; the bulk of the materials cover 1963-1992. The records are divided into two series: TOPICAL FILES and PHOTOGRAPHS.
The TTopical Filea.4 linear feet) are arranged alphabetically. The records are a good source for documenting the performances of the Friars. The "Performance Contract/Data Sheets" indicate the time and place of the performance, in addition to the amount paid to the Friars. The programs contain information on the eight members. Historical information can be gleaned from the promotional letters.
The Photogrpahs (12 folders) are arranged in chronological order. Each folder contains at least one promotional black and white photograph used by the Friars for the particular academic year.
Subjects:
Friars (Musical group); University of Michigan--Choral organizations.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan--Choral organizations.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- TOPICAL FILES
  - The Arbors, ca. 1963 ( (Box 1)
  - Audition Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1984 (Box 1)
  - Logo, undated (Box 1)
  - Member Lists, 1977, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Performance Contract/Data Sheets
    - 1964-1978 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1974-1993 (Box 1)
  - Promotional Letters, undated (Box 1)
  - Publicity Flyers, undated (Box 1)
  - Repertoire, 1967-1983 (Box 1)
  - Sounds from the Summit, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Members
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
    - undated (Box 1)